<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Relics on Oswald Jones</title>
    <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/relics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Relics on Oswald Jones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Oswald Jones</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 19:25:22 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://ojones.github.io/blog/relics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Intuit</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/relics/intuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/relics/intuit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Circa 2016, I worked at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.intuit.com/&#34;&gt;Intuit&lt;/a&gt; as a member of the QuickBooks Licenses team.  Hard to say, harder to spell, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even mean what you think it does:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/JfZfuo3C-qo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We were trying to solve a big problem in a big way.  Become the premiere information source for US government licenses on the federal, state, and city level.  Our secret sauce was an ingest flow that allowed our research team of 10+ to learn, tag, and define requirements for all major licenses in the country.  With the biggest catalog in the world, our next feat was the client app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our entire office had read The Lean Startup by Eric Ries, so we were big into the MVP paradigm.  We ran experiments every sprint, measured results, redesigned, and A/B tested to confirm a sprint or two later.  Our NPS ranged from 50 to 70.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using combination of pivotal, dropbox, and google sheets, our two week sprints began to rock.  Having a rockstar project manager and designer allowed our engineering team to open, execute, and set sail to a project every 2 or 4 weeks.  Epics were delivered according to which new feature would provide the most experimental data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 4 senior engineers including myself, we could all transition from the frontend to the backend.  There were no walls between tasks and we could easily trade work loads if it helped the sprint timeline.  This project was proof to me that Agile Scrum can work the way it promises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trick is to apply a fun and consistent sprint routine that encourages ownership.  We did it by working hand in hand with design and volunteering for agreed upon sprint goals.  Our user stories and designs were ready day one of the sprint.  Each day we wrote our task progress on a white board everyone could see.  Finished tasks were confirmed daily by management or designer and reflected in Pivotal Tracker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you know what&amp;rsquo;s done every day, you can see what&amp;rsquo;s left to do.  And when you&amp;rsquo;re rooting for eachother and there are no wall between frontend and backend, you can help eachother win every sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fox</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/relics/fox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2013 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/relics/fox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Circa 2014, I worked at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foxmovies.com/&#34;&gt;Fox&lt;/a&gt; as a member of the &amp;ldquo;Dev Dream Team.&amp;rdquo;  Everything they say about the movie business is true (even for the engineers).  Still we got to make a bunch of cool screener apps really quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team made the screener app for the Oscar&amp;rsquo;s the same year we won for 12 Years A Slave.  I just want to thank The Academy&amp;hellip; and Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://ojones.github.io/blog/blog/relics/images/12-years-a-slave.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;12 Years A Slave Won&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After making a few screener apps (web and mobile), we thought why not make a generic admin tool so anyone at Fox can share copyrighted video content.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://ojones.github.io/blog/blog/relics/images/fox_admin.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Generic Screener Admin&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This is the industry so we can&amp;rsquo;t just put things on youtube.  We have a DRM process for everything.  That takes asset management, tracking, and Telerik.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://ojones.github.io/blog/blog/relics/images/fox_asset_mgr.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;DRM Asset Manager&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;But why stop there, let&amp;rsquo;s make an asset monolith with teams from all over the world.  You give me the designs, I give you back Knockout templates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://ojones.github.io/blog/blog/relics/images/fox_control1.PNG&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Fox UI Control&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://ojones.github.io/blog/blog/relics/images/fox_control2.PNG&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Fox UI Control&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://ojones.github.io/blog/blog/relics/images/fox_control3.PNG&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Fox UI Control&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a great contract project from which I learned a lot about frontend frameworks.  But when politics are the leading priority, results can only get so good.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disney</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/relics/disney/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/relics/disney/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For almost 3 years, I worked on a top secret project for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.disneystore.com/magicband/mn/1024701/&#34;&gt;Disney&lt;/a&gt;.  They launched in late 2013.  Of all my projects, I look back upon this one with the fondness of seeing something through from begining to end.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://ojones.github.io/blog/blog/relics/images/disney.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Disney MagicBand&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Working as a consultant for Accenture, my team ran the key service upon which all others depended.  It was great to see a project go from napkin drawings to RFID chips, molds, around the world, into customer homes, and onto happy children&amp;rsquo;s wrists.  I still have mine from the first production ready batch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With tens of engineers, hundreds of service endpoints, and millions of customers, you learn a lot about what it takes to make magic.  Coordination was currency and as our dev team&amp;rsquo;s service and infrastructure liason I had my arms full.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My short experience in DevOps with Clearwire afforded our service team the credit to lead the heard of 50 or service teams.  Having a previous contract with Atlassian, I forged ahead with a Bamboo build and deployment process using Nexus.  We later moved to UDeploy which put much more power into QA and analysts hands.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://ojones.github.io/blog/blog/relics/images/Disney-MagicBand.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;RFID Guest Experience&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;And of course, we had a third party ESB and a third party cron manager.  Interacting with B2B software was beginning to take up my whole day.  Working with Java Hibernate was no picnic either, especially when our database schema was changing weekly.  Yet through challenge comes triumph, and I am ever thankful to the stakeholders of the **** project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clearwire</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/relics/clearwire/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2010 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/relics/clearwire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Circa 2011, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.clear.com/&#34;&gt;Clearwire&lt;/a&gt; had just changed their name to Clear.  That was the beginning of the end.  They were just a little ahead of their time.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://ojones.github.io/blog/blog/relics/images/clearwire.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Clearwire&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Working as a consultant for Accenture, we handled their build and deployment process.  We were using Jenson before there even was a Jenson (just Hudson), and Maven was my new best friend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/relics/microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/relics/microsoft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Circa 2010, like most Microsoft employees, I was a contractor.  Through &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.catalysis.com/&#34;&gt;Catalysis&lt;/a&gt; I worked on a some high profile projects including the Windows 7 registration page, Office 2010 registration page, and MSN.com tour.  Each of these projects were small in terms of content, but had high taffic functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://ojones.github.io/blog/blog/relics/images/office_2010.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Office 2010&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://ojones.github.io/blog/blog/relics/images/win7.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Windows 7&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The registration pages required update and insert write access.  To avoid security concerns of SQL injection (cross browser security was big then), we opted for stored procedures.  This allowed us to go heavy on database hardware while maintaining a small frontend with a secure data access layer.  If I could go back in time, I would have implemented a queue and reserved backend resources when traffic was not high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The frontend challenge was to localize Windows 7 and Office 2010 pages into over 70 languages.  Having a flexible UI to accommodate differing paragraph and input text lengths required lots of manual testing.  Making the localization performant took some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MSN.com tour was a project to promote an MSN.com redesign.  Microsoft Window&amp;rsquo;s butterfly was a key part.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://ojones.github.io/blog/blog/relics/images/msn.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;msn.com (2010)&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We contracted the hard stuff to be done in both Flash and Silverlight.  This way the functionality happened on the client.  I created a wrapper website and we deployed the Flash and Silverlight files to Rackspace.  Back then we used to talk about HTML 5 the way we talk about web assembly today.  It&amp;rsquo;s funny how time change and don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WaMu</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/relics/wamu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2007 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/relics/wamu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Circa 2007, we at &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Washington_Mutual&#34;&gt;Wamu&lt;/a&gt; (aka Washington Mutual) thought we were the coolest bank.  Cool nickname, cool kiosks.  So of course we had to have the coolest website. (Ahem, for a bank.)&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://ojones.github.io/blog/blog/relics/images/wamu_login.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;wamu.com 2008&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Hired to the Technology Leadership Program straight out of college, my first job was to work on the controls team.  We were using the latest in Microsoft ASP.NET 2.0 technology.  Remember .ascx “user controls.”  I think they&amp;rsquo;re called &amp;ldquo;components&amp;rdquo; now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I swear, can’t a button just be called a button.  How long are we as a tech community going to keep re-inventing the same thing.  I know, I know, it&amp;rsquo;s the browser&amp;rsquo;s fault.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still looking at this screenshot I see a lot to learn from.  Good contrast, accessibilty, flat (mostly).  We had the best practice of bread crumbs and user tabs, for the time at least.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>