<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Oswald Jones</title>
    <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Oswald Jones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Oswald Jones</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 19:25:22 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero To One</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/ZeroToOne/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/ZeroToOne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow, did not expect so much from a super successful serial investor, but boy was I wrong.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_Thiel&#34;&gt;Peter Thiel&lt;/a&gt; kills it in his latest &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Zero-One-Notes-Startups-Future/dp/0804139296&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does he &amp;ldquo;kill&amp;rdquo; exactly?  Pessimism.  Well at least the most popular excuses for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That alone is a good reason to read this.  It&amp;rsquo;s not a self help or make your startup rich book.  Rather it&amp;rsquo;s an intellectual frame for the future and how to take part in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It challenges popular viewpoints in economics and technology.  Even I was hurt and offended at parts.  But Thiel makes a strong case and I won&amp;rsquo;t discount his message just because I don&amp;rsquo;t see eye to eye on every line.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Master Algorithm</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/TheMasterAlgorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/TheMasterAlgorithm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://homes.cs.washington.edu/~pedrod/&#34;&gt;Pedro Domingos&lt;/a&gt; gives a valient effort to bring the complexity and potential of machine learning (ML) to the average jane.  He fails, but succeeds in telling the compelling story of ML algorithms to this point and to where they may be going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Master-Algorithm-Ultimate-Learning/dp/0465065708&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; to everyone who has an, at least, a peripheral understanding of data science.  Domingos does more than just skim the major algorithms.  He weaves their stories together in a coherent journey toward the ultimate algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coders At Work</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/CodersAtWork/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/CodersAtWork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As developers, we wander through a thick forest of technology everyday.  Lost and unsure, we wish to find the wise ones who have come before.  Surly Douglas Crockford (Javascript), Simon Peython Jones (Haskell), or the great Knuth (Art of Programming) could show us the way.  If only we had their cell number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/peter-seibel-39518a72&#34;&gt;Peter Seibel&lt;/a&gt; has been to the top of the mountain.  In his &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Coders-Work-Reflections-Craft-Programming/dp/1430219483&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; he interviews 15 of the greats on their history, their code practices and beliefs.  In effect, he attempts to answer: what is it that great programmers have in common?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t believe it if I told you, so my recommendation is to read it, and see the truth for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Rules!</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/WorkRules/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/WorkRules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first third of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.workrules.net/&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; is an unforgivable worship to Google. I almost wrote the book off as a mere marketing scheme. However, as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/laszlobock&#34;&gt;Laszlo Bock&lt;/a&gt; himself explains, Google has run a variety of experiments and collected data on things about the work place that no woman ever has before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bock clearly lays out the results of the experiments smaller companies couldn’t afford to do themselves, but can’t afford to ignore. He brings HR into the limelight and makes you want to quit your job to join the department of &amp;ldquo;people operations.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Superintelligence</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/Superintelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/Superintelligence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You would think that a tech &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Superintelligence-Dangers-Strategies-Nick-Bostrom-ebook/dp/B00LOOCGB2&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; with such a cool title on such an interesting subject coudn&amp;rsquo;t possibly lose.  But you&amp;rsquo;ll be snoring at the 40% mark.  It turns out that detailed hypotheticals about exactly how and when the world will be destroyed is not fun.  Who knew?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one saving grace that makes the whole thing worth it is the movie &amp;ldquo;Ex Machina,&amp;rdquo; which should be required after every reading.  It is doubtful that you will understand the plot of the movie without the background &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nickbostrom.com/&#34;&gt;Nick Bostrom&lt;/a&gt; gives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dry as it may be, it&amp;rsquo;s the only book I&amp;rsquo;ve found that tackles the dangers of AI seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Dysfunctions of a Team</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/5DysfunctionsOfATeam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/5DysfunctionsOfATeam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While attending a conference, I got the chance to see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tablegroup.com/pat/&#34;&gt;Patrick Lencioni&lt;/a&gt; speak about teams and their common dysfunctions.  I was impressed in the true sense of the word, and am confident he was the crowd favorite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although he made referenced his &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Five-Dysfunctions-Team-Leadership-Fable/dp/0787960756/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1454836598&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=5+disfunction%27s+of+a+team&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; as a fable, his presentation also seemed to have just given away all of the valuable facts.  What in the world was the point of reading his work of fiction now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learn more by story than fact, and Lencioni&amp;rsquo;s fable is yet another credit to that truth.  With preconceived notions that this book would not be worth the time, I picked it up off my manager&amp;rsquo;s desk just to glance.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t put it back down until it was finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through his clever tale, the lessons come to life.  Even if you are on a fantastic team (as I was) you will find that learning about the dysfunctions you will invariably encounter, to be a pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Logician and the Engineer</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/TheLogicianAndTheEngineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/TheLogicianAndTheEngineer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is hands down the most technically challenging &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Logician-Engineer-Shannon-Information/dp/0691151008&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read.  After reading The Information by James Gleick, I became enamored with Claude Shannon, discoverer of the bit, and father of the information age.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_J._Nahin&#34;&gt;Paul J. Nahin&lt;/a&gt; makes the strong case that the lion&amp;rsquo;s share of credit originates with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Boole&#34;&gt;George Boole&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nahin accomplishes this by enumerating the boundless applications of boolean algebra.  He unapologetically tours the reader through complex riddles that would have daunted Einstein, but come apart like magic for the electrical engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually don&amp;rsquo;t recommend this book.  It&amp;rsquo;s a pain, boring, and impractical.  Still Nahin&amp;rsquo;s passion for boolean algebra is touching, even facinating.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Owns The Future</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/WhoOwnsTheFuture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/WhoOwnsTheFuture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jaronlanier.com/&#34;&gt;Jaron Lanier&lt;/a&gt; represents the opposite side of the spectrum from Ray Kurzweil, and in some ways, just as extreme.  Known as the man who coined the phrase &amp;ldquo;virtual reality,&amp;rdquo; he&amp;rsquo;s played a sorted part in the history of computer science and is currently at Microsoft Research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the information age, is it any wonder that the companies that gather the most data on indiviuals in society are the richest?  And if we live in such an age, why are we giving our information away for free to these mega servers (Google, Amazon, Facebook)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lanier&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Who-Owns-Future-Jaron-Lanier/dp/1451654979&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; is an almalgamation of his perspective on technology, econmics and the future.  Instead of fearing the AI singularity, which he feels is laughable, Lanier believes that society must take ownership of their online data, before the &amp;ldquo;siren servers&amp;rdquo; destroy our economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lanier&amp;rsquo;s claim&amp;rsquo;s that these economic concerns and solutions are not predictions, but eventuallities.  His hope is that we learn our economic lessons sooner, rather than after a century long recession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, it&amp;rsquo;s tough to make the call.  Lanier or Kurzweil.  Kurzeil or Lanier.  Both have been around so long and seen so much.  Both are renegades headed in opposite directions.  I think they go great together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Google Works</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/HowGoogleWorks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2014 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/HowGoogleWorks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How do you compete for fame with Larry Page and Sergey Brin?  &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eric_Schmidt&#34;&gt;Eric Schmidt&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jonathan_Rosenberg_(technologist&#34;&gt;Jonathan Rosenber&lt;/a&gt;), with the help of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/alaneagle&#34;&gt;Alan Eagle&lt;/a&gt;, take a stab at in their book on how Google works, titled: How Google Works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/How-Google-Works-Eric-Schmidt/dp/1455582344&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; succeeds as an insider perspective about Google.  But as a professional engineer you can&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder what parts are legit, and what is just self congratulating wishful thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The employment strategy of hiring the best is a big theme.  The authors introduce their revolutionary notion of a &amp;ldquo;smart creative.&amp;rdquo;  One, she is a brilliant worker who doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to have a PHd, but could easily get one if she wanted to.  Two, she is passionate about her crafts, of which she has many.  To paraphrase a couple of criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors paint a pretty picture of the smart startup that broke all the rules to redefine the game.  And in the face of Google&amp;rsquo;s success, who&amp;rsquo;s to say they are wrong.  Skepticism aside, it&amp;rsquo;s a great industry perspective done by a great team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alan Turing: The Enigma</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/AlanTuringTheEnigma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/AlanTuringTheEnigma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So you want to know the whole life story of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Turing&#34;&gt;Alan Turing&lt;/a&gt;?  Are you sure?  Well then you&amp;rsquo;ll love &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.synth.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Andrew Hodges&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; biographical &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Alan-Turing-Enigma-Andrew-Hodges/dp/1491587997&#34;&gt;marathon&lt;/a&gt;. (And yes it was the basis for the movie.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book divulges every intimate detail of Alan Turing&amp;rsquo;s life and death.  Of which, computer science was just one part.  His paper on The Imitation Game, in which he outlines the de facto standard for artificial intelligence, is the least of his accomplishments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hodges leaves no stone unturned.  While the movie falsely portrays Turing as a socially inept genius stereotype, his true dreamer is charming.  Love, war, prejudice, loss.  Ahead of his time in so many ways, this biography celebrates the achievement of much more than a father to computer science.  But that of an incredible human spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Information</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/TheInformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/TheInformation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This may be the most important &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Information-History-Theory-Flood/dp/1400096235&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; ever written.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://around.com/&#34;&gt;James Gleick&lt;/a&gt; skillfully tells the story of, well, everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever felt like there is something bigger out there.  Bigger than you.  Bigger than society.  Behind the random entropy of happenstance,  there is something at work.  And it&amp;rsquo;s growing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Species come and go, but The Information is forever.  So what does this mean to the mortal human of today?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve often heard that you have to know your history to know your future.  I thought that was just something that history professor&amp;rsquo;s said to defend their diminishing economic utility.  But Gleick artfully illustrates how our world is most influenced by a background song that never ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the tune from indigenous Africa, passed Ada Lovelace, and through Richard Dawkins, Gleick clues us into what&amp;rsquo;s really going on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Create A Mind</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/HowToCreateAMind/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/HowToCreateAMind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kurzweilai.net/ray-kurzweil-biography&#34;&gt;Ray Kurzweil&lt;/a&gt; does it again, and even better this time.  Unlike The Singularity Is Near, this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/How-Create-Mind-Thought-Revealed/dp/1491518839&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; pulls no punches for the technically timmid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kurzweil explains his controversial confidence that the way to AI is by reconstructing the human brain as a digital algorithm.  In fact, he asserts that for as complicated as the brain is, there may be only one algorithm at work.  And WHEN we do find it, there is no technical reason for why it can’t be duplicated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not betting the whole farm on any particular algorithm, he highlights the promise of Hidden Markov Models and potentials of modern neural networks.  (I don&amp;rsquo;t think the term deep learning was as en vogue at the time of writing.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than committing to a solution, Kurzweil admirably postulates that there must be a solution, and it is inevitable that we will find it soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is what took me to the next level and got me into machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>