<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Oswald Jones</title>
    <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Oswald Jones</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Oswald Jones</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 19:25:22 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Master Algorithm</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/TheMasterAlgorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/TheMasterAlgorithm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://homes.cs.washington.edu/~pedrod/&#34;&gt;Pedro Domingos&lt;/a&gt; gives a valient effort to bring the complexity and potential of machine learning (ML) to the common man.  He fails, but succeeds in telling the compelling story of ML algorithms to this point and to where they may be going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Master-Algorithm-Ultimate-Learning/dp/0465065708&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; to everyone who has an, at least, a peripheral understanding of data science.  Domingos does more than just skim the major algorithms.  He weaves their stories together in a coherent journey toward the ultimate algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coders At Work</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/CodersAtWork/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/CodersAtWork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As developers, we wander through a thick forest of technology everyday.  Lost and unsure, we wish to find the wise ones who have come before.  Surly Douglas Crockford (Javascript), Simon Peython Jones (Haskell), or the great Knuth (Art of Programming) could show us the way.  If only we had their cell number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/peter-seibel-39518a72&#34;&gt;Peter Seibel&lt;/a&gt; has been to the top of the mountain.  In his &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Coders-Work-Reflections-Craft-Programming/dp/1430219483&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; he interviews 15 of the greats on their history, their code practices and beliefs.  In effect, he attempts to answer: what is it that great programmers have in common?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t believe it if I told you, so my recommendation is to read it, and see the truth for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Rules!</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/WorkRules/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/WorkRules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first third of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.workrules.net/&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; is an unforgivable worship to Google. I almost wrote the book off as a mere marketing scheme. However, as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/laszlobock&#34;&gt;Laszlo Bock&lt;/a&gt; himself explains, Google has run a variety of experiments and collected data on things about the work place that no woman ever has before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bock clearly lays out the results of the experiments smaller companies couldn’t afford to do themselves, but can’t afford to ignore. He brings HR into the limelight and makes you want to quit your job to join the people operations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Superintelligence</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/Superintelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/Superintelligence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You would think that a tech &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Superintelligence-Dangers-Strategies-Nick-Bostrom-ebook/dp/B00LOOCGB2&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; with such a cool title on such an interesting subject coudn&amp;rsquo;t possibly lose.  But you&amp;rsquo;ll be snoring at the 40% mark.  It turns out that detailed hypotheticals about exactly how and when the world will be destroyed is not fun.  Who knew?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one saving grace that makes the whole thing worth it is the movie &amp;ldquo;Ex Machina,&amp;rdquo; which should be required after every reading.  It is doubtful that you will understand the plot of the movie without the background &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nickbostrom.com/&#34;&gt;Nick Bostrom&lt;/a&gt; gives.  Dry as it may be, it&amp;rsquo;s the only book I&amp;rsquo;ve found that tackles the dangers of AI seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Dysfunctions of a Team</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/5DysfunctionsOfATeam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/5DysfunctionsOfATeam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While attending an Intuit conference, I got the chance to see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tablegroup.com/pat/&#34;&gt;Patrick Lencioni&lt;/a&gt; speak about teams and their common dysfunctions.  I was impressed in the true sense of the word, and I&amp;rsquo;m confident he was the crowd favorite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although he had referenced his &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Five-Dysfunctions-Team-Leadership-Fable/dp/0787960756/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1454836598&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=5+disfunction%27s+of+a+team&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; as a fable, he also seemed to have just presented all of the valuable details.  What in the world was the point of reading his work of fiction now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learn more by story than fact, and Lencioni&amp;rsquo;s fable is yet another credit to that truth.  With a preconceived notion that the book would not be worth the time, I picked it up off my manager&amp;rsquo;s desk just to glance.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t put back down until it was finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through his clever tale, the lessons come to life.  Even if you are on a fantastic team, as I was, you will find that learning about the dysfunctions you will invariably encounter, to be a pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Logician and the Engineer</title>
      <link>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/TheLogicianAndTheEngineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 19:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ojones.github.io/blog/books/TheLogicianAndTheEngineer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is hands down the most technically challenging &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Logician-Engineer-Shannon-Information/dp/0691151008&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read.  After reading The Information by James Gleik, I became enamored with Claude Shannon, discoverer of the bit, and father of the information age.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_J._Nahin&#34;&gt;Paul J. Nahin&lt;/a&gt; makes the strong case that the lion&amp;rsquo;s share of credit originates with George Bool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nahin accomplishes by enumerating the boundless applications of boolean algebra.  He unapologetically tours the reader through complex riddles that would daunt Albert Einstein, but come apart like magic for the electrical engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually don&amp;rsquo;t recommend this book.  It&amp;rsquo;s a pain, boring, and impractical.  Still Nahin&amp;rsquo;s passion for boolean algebra is touching, even facinating.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>